NISHAT MAHMUD

FRONT-END DEVELOPER



- 🛪 <u>nishatrhythm.github.io</u>
- ™ nishatrhythm@gmail.com
- +8801538868973

About Me

A dedicated, self-assured, and eager learner with a constant desire to acquire new abilities. Possessing expertise in Graphic Design, Web Development, and Android Development, I aim to apply my knowledge and experience in these areas. Seeking opportunities to serve a professional organization with sincere devotion, diligence, and commitment. Additionally, I have five years of experience managing a YouTube channel, providing me with skills in video editing.

Education

Jagannath University, Dhaka - B.Sc

Computer Science and Engineering

2020 - Present **Grade : CGPA**

In my third year of pursuing a B.Sc degree in Computer Science and Engineering at my university life, I have developed a deep understanding of various computer science topics, including programming, algorithms, data structures, database management, and web development.

Govt. Ananda Mohon College, Mymensingh – HSC

Group of Science

2017 - 2019

Grade: GPA 5.00

During my time at college, I experienced a challenging and stimulating academic environment that fostered the expansion of my knowledge and the development of critical thinking skills.

Mymensingh Zilla School - SSC

Group of Science

2009 - 2017

Grade: GPA 5.00

At my school life, I pursued studies in the Science group, benefiting from a comprehensive education that equipped me with the necessary skills and knowledge for my academic and professional endeavors ahead.



Skills



















Tools

ADOBE XD

FIGMA

GIT

ANDROID STUDIO

MICROSOFT OFFICE

ADOBE ACROBAT

ADOBE PHOTOSHOP

ADOBE PREMIERE PRO

ADOBE ILLUSTRATOR

NISHAT MAHMUD

GRAPHICS DESIGNER



Experience

Go Bangladesh — Co-founder

Front-End Developer

2021 - Present

Having joined "Go Bangladesh" as a Front-End developer, I have been actively involved in collaborating with designers, back-end developers, and clients since 2021 to create seamless and intuitive user experiences for their innovative smart solutions in the mass transportation system of Bangladesh.

Wikitricks - Founder

Content Creator

2018 - Present

Throughout the past five years, I have skillfully curated and managed a captivating YouTube channel, meticulously creating and sharing engaging videos that have captivated audiences, leading to substantial growth and enhanced viewer interaction.

Certifications

- JnU Intra University Programming Contest, 2023
- Bright Skills Limited (Adobe Photoshop Master Course)
- Bright Skills Limited (MS Excel Biginner to Advanced)
- Bright Skills Limited (MS PowerPoint Advance Course)
- Bright Skills Limited (Professional Content Writing)
- Bright Skills Limited (Spoken English)
- Creative IT Institute (Training on Blockchain)
- ICPC Asia Dhaka Regional Site Online Preliminary Contest 2020-21
- MuktoPaath (Coronavirus Disease, COVID-19)
- Bangladesh Physics Olympiad 2018 (Regional Round)
- Bangladesh Botany Olympiad 2017 (Mymensingh Division)
- Bangladesh Mathematical Olympiad 2016 (Regional Round)
- Bangladesh Mathematical Olympiad 2014 (Regional Round)
- Bangladesh Mathematical Olympiad 2013 (Regional Round)
- Bangladesh Mathematical Olympiad 2012 (Regional Round)
- Bangladesh Mathematical Olympiad 2011 (Regional Round)

February 2023
(Segment : Project Showcase, Senior)

CHAMPION — MBSTU Robo Tech Olympiad, Tangail

Honors and Awards

Issued by Mawlana Bhashani Science & Technology University

CHAMPION — MBSTU Robo Tech Olympiad, Tangail

(Segment: Idea Presentation)

Issued by Mawlana Bhashani Science & Technology University

1ST RUNNER-UP — An Apps Showcasing Competition

November 2022

Issued by Jagannath University IT Society

1ST RUNNER-UP — NACTAR Robotics Olympiad, Bogura

August 2022

(Segment : Project Showcase, Senior)

Issued by National Computer Training and Research Academy

1ST RUNNER-UP — RUET CSE FEST-2K22

June 2022

(Segment : Project Showcase, Software)

Issued by Rajshahi University of Engineering & Technology

2ND RUNNER-UP — RUET CSE FEST-2K22

June 2022

(Segment : Idea/Poster Presentation)

Issued by Rajshahi University of Engineering & Technology

1ST RUNNER-UP — The Hult Prize 2022 Challenge

March 2022

Issued by Hult Prize

10 LAC BDT FUND

February 2022

As a startup project, "Go Bangladesh" got a 10 lac BDT fund from the Innovation Design and Entrepreneurship Academy (iDEA) project of the ICT Division.

TOP 30 — Mujib 100 Idea Contest

December 2021

On the 100th Birth Anniversary of the Father of the Nation of Bangladesh, Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujibur Rahman and the 50th anniversary of independence of the country, the University Grant Commission (UGC) organized it.

2ND RUNNER-UP

August 2017

Science Workshop and Quiz Program on the occasion of 50 years birthday celebration of Marie Curie.

Issued by Bangladesh Agricultural University Science Club

View All Certificates